Guide to the Mary Roberts Rinehart Papers, 1831-1970 SC.1958.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Published Works, 1904-1983; IV.
  - Works by Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1904-1983; 1.
    - U-V, 1908-1912 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - W, 1926-1939 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "The Wall", 1938 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Y, 1910-1937 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Brown scrap book - clippings of published poems and stories, 1904-1905 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Red scrapbook - clippings of published stories, 1905 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Photostatic copy of "The Detective Story," a poem by Mary Roberts Rinehart, is inserted.
    - "Dorothy klæder sig om til middag, af" ["Dorothy Dresses for Dinner"] in Hjemmet nr. 8, February 22, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - "The Frightened Wife" - first of four parts - in The Saturday Evening Post vol. 225 no. 33, February 14, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - "Het testament van een jonge vrouw" ["The Frightened Wife"] in Panorama 40ste Jaarg. no 45, November 6, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "I går var som en lycklig dröm" in Vårt hem Nummer 47 Argang 30, November 19, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "Klockan 4 på morgonen" in Vårt hem Nummer 37 Argang 31, September 16, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "Phoenix in New England" in Town & Country vol. 103 no. 4322, July 1949 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Skandalen" in Vårt hem Nummer 48 Argang 30, November 26, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "The Woman Behind the Soldier" in McClure's vol. 50 no. 6, April 1918 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "Mary Roberts Rinehart Shows How Truth is Stranger than Fiction" (Map-case 1, Drawer 7)
      Oversize, fragile. See user photocopies also in this series.
  - Works about Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1916-1968; 2.
    This subseries contains clippings of articles written about Mary Roberts Rinehart. Larger clippings and magazines are housed in an oversize box, Box 32.
    - Alger, Edwin - "Who's Behind the Name", November 8, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Transcript of radio broadcast on Mary Roberts Rinehart.
    - Clemens, Cyril- "A Visit to Mary Roberts Rinehart" in Biography vol. 8 no. 47, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Includes draft manuscript and letter from Cyril Clemens.
    - Landon, Joseph-"Rinehart Novel Appeal", August 5, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Television script about Mary Roberts Rinehart's writing of The After House, for the Bell System's Telephone Time program on ABC-TV. Includes photographs of Claudette Colbert as Mary Roberts Rinehart.
    - Young, JoAnn-"Mary Roberts Rinehart's Psychic Adventures" in Fate vol. 12 no. 9 iss. 114, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Articles about Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1916-1938 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Articles about Mary Roberts Rinehart (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Magazines with articles about Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1931-1932 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Contains issues of Save the Surface Magazine, The Writer, The Writer's Own Magazine.
    - Magazines with articles about Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1950, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Contains issues of Cue, Current Biography, Nursing World.
    - Material related to planned television program about Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1966-1968 (Box 15, Folder 9-12)
      Notes, scripts, and correspondence between Tom Ashwell, KDKA-TV producer, and Rinehart sons. Program was never produced. Material donated to University of Pittsburgh by Gordon Ramsey, 1972.
    - Articles by and about Stanley M. Rinehart, Jr., 1936, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Contains issue of Current Biography
    - Hellman, Geoffrey T.-"Mary Roberts Rinehart" in Life vol. 20 no. 8, February 25, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Palmer, Gretta - "I Had Cancer" in Ladies' Home Journal vol. LXIV no. 7, July 1947 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Clippings of articles about Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1927-1934 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Clippings of articles about Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1934-1938 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      Includes issue of Saturday Review of Literature, undated clippings, and milk carton with Mary Roberts Rinehart biography.
- Contracts and Business Records, 1906-1962; V.
  This series comprises contracts assigning rights to Mary Roberts Rinehart's works. Documents pertain to serial rights, book publication rights, foreign publication and translation rights, dramatization rights, dramatic production rights, motion picture rights, radio broadcast rights, and television rights. Agreements are between Mary Roberts Rinehart and various companies and individuals, which are generally listed in the scope and content note for each folder. Included with contracts are related correspondence, statements of payment, and other documents. Also included in this series are business records of Mary Roberts Rinehart that record works sold, rights sold, and prices.
  - Magazine publishing and serial rights, 1921-1924 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Parties include McClure's Magazine, Inc., Maximilian Elser for Metropolitan Newspaper Service, Robert H. Davis for The Frank A. Munsey Company.
  - Publication and dramatic rights assigned to The Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1909-1913 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Publishing rights assigned to Houghton Mifflin Company, 1913-1918 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Book publishing rights assigned to George H. Doran Company and Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1915-1928 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Includes contract with Stanley M. Rinehart.
  - Publication rights asigned to Farrar & Rinehart and Rinehart and Co., 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Includes one book publishing agreement with The Writer, Inc., 1939.
  - Book publication rights in Great Britain, 1915-1950 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Parties include Smith Elder & Co., Hodder and Stoughton, Cassell & Company, Farrar & Rinehart, Rinehart & Co.
  - Foreign publication and translation rights, 1915-1944 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Parties include Curtis Brown, Gyldendalske Boghandel, Ullstein Verlag, Casa Editrice A. Monadori, Palladis R.T., Albert Bonnier.
  - Agreements with Mrs. H.C. (Beatrice) DeMille, Cecil B. DeMille, and the DeMille Company regarding dramatic works, 1906-1912 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Dramatization and dramatic production rights, 1906-1916 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Parties include T.M. Harton and George M. Harton, C.M. Blanchard and H.W. Brown, Mrs. H.C. DeMille for "Rinehart Roberts" (Mary Roberts Rinehart pseudonym), Henry B. Harris, the Office of Winthrop Ames.
  - Motion picture rights, 1915-1919 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Parties include Essanay Film Manufacturing Company, George H. Doran, Famous Players Film Company, Paramount Pictures, Inc., R.L. Giffen, Samuel Goldwyn, Rex Beach, Eminent Authors Pictures, Inc.
  - Motion picture rights, 1924-1947 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Parties include Famous Players-Lasky Corporation, First National Pictures Inc., Arthur Maude, Douglas MacLean, Fox Film Corporation, Warner Bros. First National Productions Limited.
  - Motion picture rights assigned to Warner Bros. Pictures for "One Hour of Glory" and "The Dog in the Orchard", 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Radio broadcast agreements for The Trumpet Sounds and The Window at the White Cat, 1910-1941 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Parties include Stephens College, Farrar & Rinehart, Funk & Wagnalls Company, Knox Reeves Advertising, Bobbs-Merrill Company.
  - Television rights, 1952-1956 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Parties include Nathan Kroll, CBS Television, Columbia Broadcasting System, MCA, Curtis Brown, Bischoff-Diamond Corporation, Mercury Publications, Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine.
  - Dramatic production and motion picture rights to The Amazing Interlude, 1918-1940 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Parties include Edward E. Rose, Klaw & Erlanger, George C. Tyler, Frank C. Reilly
  - Dramatic production and motion picture rights to The Bat, 1920-1952 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Parties include Avery Hopwood, Lincoln Wagenhals, Collin Kemper, Wagenhals & Kemper, Anna Belle Elliot, Samuel French, Harry Brand, Art Cinema Corporation, Trans-Canada Theatres.
  - Dramatic production and motion picture rights to The Breaking Point, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Parties include Wagenhals & Kemper, Lincoln A. Wagenhals, Collin Kemper, Caroline F. Wagenhals, Louise B. Kemper, Famous Players-Lasky Corporation.
  - Publication, motion picture, and radio broadcast rights to The Circular Staircase, 1908-1956 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Parties include The Bobbs-Merrill Company, Doubleday, Doran & Company, Selig Polyscope Company, The George H. Doran Company, CBS Television.
  - Correspondence and agreements related to motion picture rights to The Circular Staircase held by Selig Polyscope Company, 1913-1922 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Correspondents include Mary Roberts Rinehart, Stanley Marshall Rinehart, George H. Doran, The Bobbs-Merrill Company, R.L. Giffen for Alice Kauser, Wagenhals & Kemper.
  - Motion picture rights to Long Live the King assigned to Jackie Coogan Productions, 1923, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Includes related correspondence and clipping.
  - Motion picture rights to Miss Pinkerton assigned to Warner Bros. Pictures and United Artists Associates, 1932, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Dramatization and dramatic production rights to Seven Days, 1909-1931 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Parties include Avery Hopwood, Mrs. H.C. DeMille, Wagenhals & Kemper Company, Selwyn & Company, A. Folmer Hansen, Samuel French.
  - Book publishing, motion picture, and radio broadcast rights to various "Tish" works, 1911-1962 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Parties include The Bobbs-Merrill Company, Houghton Mifflin Company, George H. Doran Company, Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Corporation, Loew's Incorporated, Edward Rose, Augustus Pitou. Also contains correspondence.
  - Dramatization and dramatic production rights to various "Tish" works, 1918, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Parties include Edward E. Rose, Augustus Pitou, Inc., Samuel French.
  - Documents related to incorporation and dissolution of Mary Roberts Rinehart Incorporated, 1923-1929 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Includes tax returns and correspondence.
  - Index cards recording the rights to works by Mary Roberts Rinehart (Box 18, Carton 1)
    - A-F (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - G-R (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - S-Y (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Notebook recording sales of early works, 1904-1905 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Notebook was in an envelope with fountain pen. Pen and envelope are in Realia series; photocopy of of explanatory note from envelope is with notebook.
  - Lists of works with information on rights, use, and potential use, 1926-1938 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Folder also contains two certificates of copyright registration.
- Correspondence, 1912-1958; VI.
  This series includes professional and personal correspondence between Mary Roberts Rinehart and various individuals. Rinehart spent a great deal of time responding to her mail. The series contains carbon copies of many letters written by Rinehart, as well as letters written by Dr. Rinehart and by Rinehart's long-time secretary William Sladen on her behalf. Much of the correspondence is between Rinehart and editors and publishers with whom she had professional relationships over several years, such as George Lorimer of The Saturday Evening Post, Loring Schuler of Ladies' Home Journal, and her sons Stan and Ted Rinehart of Farrar & Rinehart. Also included are letters from readers, some of whom were also public figures in their own right. Highlights include letters from Theordore Roosevelt, other U.S. presidents and their wives, and Sir Arthur Conan Doyle.
  - A, 1920-1951 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    George Ade, Franklin P. Adams, Adrian College, American Foundation for the Blind, American Merchant Marine Library Association, American Nurses' Association, Arlington National Cemetery
  - "The After House", 1914 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence between Thomas M.C. Bram and Roger L. Scaife.
  - Alice Kauser, 1915-1930 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Bulk of correspondence is from R.L. Giffen, Manager, Alice Kauser Motion Picture Department.
  - Alice Kauser, 1919-1920 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Primarily royalty statements from R.L. Giffen, Manager, Alice Kauser Motion Picture Department.
  - The Amazing Interlude, 1926-1929 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Primarily correspondence with Frank C. Reilly. Includes clippings.
  - American Play Company, 1928-1938 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Ames, Winthrop, 1913-1917 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Ba - Be, 1920-1953 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    "Bab" television rights, Irving Bacheller, Belgian medal
  - Baldwin, Faith, 1948-1956 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Bar Harbor, 1940-1954 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Bat, 1919-1921 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Primarily correspondence with and royalty statements from Wagenhals & Kemper.
  - The Bat, 1921-1922 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - The Bat, 1932-1954 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Primarily royalty statements from Samuel French and Co-National Plays.
  - The Bat, 1920-1953 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Primarily clippings and programs.
  - Beach, Rex, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Belasco, David, 1914-1918 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Bl - Bu, 1915-1956 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Maud Ballington Booth, Harold "Hal" Boyle, A.L. Burt Company.
  - Breen, F.S. and Carolyn/Caroline, 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - C, 1919-1956 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    James Branch Cabell, Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, Howard Chandler Christy, Irvin S. Cobb, Conference on Crime, George Creel.
  - Chapman, William Gerard, 1919-1943 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "The Confession", 1912 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Folder includes handwritten confession on which the story is based.
  - Coolidge, Calvin, October 26, 1923 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Coolidge, Grace (Mrs. Calvin), 1924-1929 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Cosmopolitan, 1937-1946 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    Primarily correspondence from Percy Waxman.
  - Curtis Brown International Publishing Bureau, 1914-1915 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Curtis Brown International Publishing Bureau, 1915-1916 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Curtis Brown International Publishing Bureau, 1916-1917 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Curtis Brown International Publishing Bureau, 1918-1920 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - D, 1918-1954 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    Richard Harding Davis, Frank Dazey, George H. Doran, Arthur Conan Doyle.
  - Davis, George N., 1940-1950 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Davis, Robert H. "Bob", 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - DeMille, Mrs. H.C. (Beatrice) and Cecil B., 1913-1921 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Disarmament conference, 1921 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Conference is also known as Washington Naval Conference and other names. Folder includes clippings of articles by Mary Roberts Rinehart.
  - The Door, 1930-1931 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    Primarily excerpts from fan mail.
  - E, 1931-1956 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    George Eastman, Ekco Products Company, Ely (information about the Rinehart's Washington, D.C. house).
  - Eisenhower, Dwight, November 9, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine, 1941-1954 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Essanay Film Manufacturing Company, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - F, 1920-1953 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Mrs. Albert B. Fall, Federal World Government, Finnish Relief Fund, flying saucers (Edward R. Murrow radio broadcast transcript), French Society of Authors and Composers (Societe des Auteurs et Compositeurs Dramatique), Frick Art Reference Library.
  - Farrar & Rinehart, 1934-1945 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Stanley M. Rinehart Jr., Frederick R. Rinehart (Mary Roberts Rinerhart's sons); John Farrar.
  - "Finders Keepers", 1927 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - G, 1921-1956 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Alumni Association of George Washington University, Girl Scouts of the United States of America, Denis Green, The Grolier Society, Frank Gruber.
  - Good Housekeeping, 1929-1932 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Arthur McKeogh, W. F. Bigelow
  - Good Housekeeping, 1932-1945 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Arthur McKeogh, W. F. Bigelow.
  - "The Great Mistake", 1940-1941 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Primarily letters from readers, including Zachariah Chafee Jr., George Creel, and Edward Dermot Doyle.
  - Ha - Hel, 1920-1956 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Moss Hart, Health Colony Club of Pittsburgh, William Randolph Hearst.
  - Her - Hu, 1919-1956 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Joseph Hergesheimer, Louis W. Hill, Frank S. Hogan, Reverend Alleyne Howell.
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1931-1958 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    Includes Lou Henry Hoover (Mrs. Herbert Hoover) and The Hoover Institute and Library.
  - Hopwood, Avery, 1913-1921 (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
  - Inaugural Committee, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - J, 1927-1956 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    Will James, Junior Literary Guild.
  - Johnston, Agnes Christine, 1949-1951 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - K, 1916-1950 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    Kauffman's Department Store, W. Langdon Kihn.
  - King Features Syndicate, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - L, 1915-1954 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    Includes Library of Congress library card, Martin Lamont / Lamont Cinevision, Herbert Lehman, Harold Lloyd, Longines-Wittnauer Watch Company.
  - Ladies' Home Journal, 1917-1931 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Loring Schuler.
  - Ladies' Home Journal, 1931-1947 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Ma - Mc, 1929-1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    University of Maine, Bank of the Manhattan Company, Mark Twain Society.
  - MacDonald, Roberta, Ruby, and Sydney, 1922-1956 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Corporation, 1934-1941 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Mi - My, 1939-1956 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Edward R. Murrow, Mystery Writers of America.
  - Moore, Martin L. and Eva, 1952-1954 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - N, 1920-1953 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    National Tuberculosis Association, Mrs. Ethelbert Nevin (Anne Paul Nevin), The New England Society of Pennsylvania. Letter from Dr. Stanley J.G. Nowak includes Mary Roberts Rinehart's medical history.
  - Navy Department, 1917-1918 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Josephus Daniels, Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  - Lord Northcliffe, 1915-1930 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Nursing and Red Cross, 1915, 1918 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Croix Rouge de Belgique, American Red Cross, Pittsburgh Training School for Nurses.
  - O, 1919, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    [Includes correspondence with lawyer about will.]
  - P, 1918-1956 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Frederick G. Payne, Pennsylvania State Museum, People's Foundation, John Pershing, William Lyon Phelps, ZaSu Pitts, Pittsburgh Sun-Telegraph, Plaza Art Auction Rooms, Reginald Pound.
  - Paramount Pictures, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - The Parker Pen Company, 1930-1953 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Public Domain Commission, 1929-1933 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Full name of commission is Commission on the Conservation and Administration of the Public Domain. Folder includes letter from Herbert Hoover.
  - R, 1931-1956 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Rinehart, Roberts, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Rolls Royce.
  - Roberts family history, 1913-1921 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1916-1918 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Folder includes autograph letter signed by Theodore Roosevelt, typescript, proof, communications from Corinne Roosevelt Robinson (Mrs. Douglas Robinson).
  - Sa - Si, 1931-1954 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Rafael Sabatini, Salvation Army, Mrs. J. Verner Scaife (Mary), Sherry Netherland Hotel.
  - Sm - Sw, 1936-1954 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Social Register Association, Social Security Agency, Lawrence E. Spivak, State Department.
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1913 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    George Lorimer, Churchill Williams.
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1914 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1915 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1916 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1917 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1917-1922 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1923-1925 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1926-1927 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1927-1929 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1930-1933 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1937-1940 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1941-1949 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1952-1954 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Saturday Evening Post - payment statements, 1919-1949 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Schwebel, Jacob J., 1923-1950 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Jacob J. Schwebel was the attorney for Avery Hopwood's estate. Folder includes correspondence with Wagenhals & Kemper, Samuel French, Farrar & Rinehart; some documentation of Rinehart v. Kemper lawsuit.
  - Selwyn & Company, 1914-1917 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Seven Days, 1914-1940 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    Folder includes correspondence with Jacob J. Schwebel, Elizabeth Marbury, Wagenhals & Kemper, American Play Company.
    A scrapbook of clippings of reviews of Seven Days, titled What the Newspapers Say of Seven Days, is shelved in Special Collections, call number PS3535.I73 .S4 1909.
  - Spadea Syndicate / James V. Spadea, 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Spiritualism, 1921-1926 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    Transcripts and notes from seances.
  - Spiritualism, 1924-1930 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Arthur Conan Doyle, H. Dennis Bradley.
  - T, 1948-1954 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Admiral Robert A. Theobald, Theta Sigma Phi.
  - "Tish" stories, 1938-1943 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Fan mail, review, business correspondence.
  - "The Trumpet Sounds", 1926-1931 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "Twenty-three and a Half Hours' Leave", 1928-1938 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Two Flights Up, 1927-1928 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - U, 1948, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    United World Federalists, Useppa Island Club.
  - Unknown (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Wa - Wil, 1944-1954 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Wagenhals & Kemper, 1913-1923 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Wagenhals & Kemper, 1921-1934 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Wagenhals & Kemper, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Wagenhals & Kemper, 1922-1923 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Watkins, Ann / Ann Watkins, Inc., 1925-1931 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Wis - Wy, 1922-1953 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Fred A. Wish, World Government News.
  - World War I, 1915-1918 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - World War I, 1917-1918 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - World War I, 1915-1920 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - World War I, 1916-1918 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - World War I, 1915, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - World War I-permits and passes, 1915, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - World War I-internal army report on observation trip in France, March 9, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    "Report of Observation Trip through S.O.R." to Major Genearl Edwin F. Glenn from Assistant to Chief of Staff, 83d Div., N.A.
  - World War I, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    Includes photographs, itinerary for tour of hospitals and other facilities.
  - World War I-Dr. Stanley M. Rinehart, 1917-1918 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    Primarily correspondence received by Dr. Rinehart while serving in the U.S. Army.
  - World War I - family correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 27, Folder 1-4)
  - World War II, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Writers' War Board / Writers' War Committee, U.S. Treasury Department.
  - World War II, 1942-1943 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Writers' War Board, Office of War Information.
  - World War II, 1943-1944 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    Writers' War Board.
  - World War II, 1944-1946 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Writers' War Board, National War Fund.
  - Y, 1941-1950 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Yeatman family - Robert, Martin, Sylvia, Harry.
  - The Yellow Room, 1945-1946 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    Letters to and from readers.
- Photographs and Artwork, 1875-circa 1948; VII.
  This series contains photographs, drawings, prints, and paintings. Subjects include Mary Roberts Rinehart and her family, other individuals, buildings, and places. The drawings, prints, and paintings are primarily illustrations for Mary Roberts Rinehart's works.
  - Photographs and Illustrations, 1875-circa 1948; 1.